Parth Suthar

(647) 739-9188 | parth.suthar1@uoit.net 92 Hutcherson Sq., M1B 1C6, Toronto, ON github.com/suthar26 linkedin.com/in/parth-suthar

Objective

To utilize my past experiences and knowledge to achieve an internship position starting this May for 12-16 months, while gaining valuable knowledge and work experience from professional engineers while challenging myself in the field of Software Engineering.

Skills

Java	CSS	PowerShell	PHP	Solidworks
Android	SQL	Express.js	Python	XML
Git	Linux	Agile	C++	React
JavaScript	Full Stack	Angular	С	Batch
HTML	Node.js	Jade	Matlab	Bash

Relevant Experience

Android Developer, Sidekick

May 2017 - September 2017

Katla Labs, Toronto, ON

- Implement Google APIs to the application to increase the app usability to increase the user base.
- Improved the Native Android app interface by fixing bugs and other problems reported on Firebase for a better user interface
- Get user feedback to modify the app and add new features to the app accordingly

Camp councillor

July 2016 - August 2016

Brick Works Academy, Toronto, ON

 Managed a robotics camp for kids age 9-14 teaching them LEGO EV3 programming along side some robotics fundamentals

Mentor/Volunteer/Planning Committee Chair

Sept. 2012 - Present

FIRST Robotics

- Take care of the logistics for the robotics event held at UOIT/DC by communicating details between Durham College/UOIT and FIRST Canada to have the best possible event at Durham College
- During FIRST Robotics Competition, assist teams regarding robot code and electrical control systems to ensure the robot works effectively during the competition
- During Build season, offer expertise in control systems, strategy and programming to high school team that I have acquired over the years as a student on a FIRST Robotics Team
- Inspired interest in STEM for FRC, FLL and Jr. FLL teams through volunteering at competitions and being a good role model by helping teams and ensuring the competitions are run smoothly

Team President/ Control Systems Lead/Web Development Lead

Sept. 2012 - April 2015

Team 188 Woburn Robotics

- Managed the team by communicating information between the mentors and students verbally to ensure good productivity between students
- Coordinated meetings and designated work plans to sub-teams to meet weekly goals
- Managed electrical and pneumatics components such as power distribution board, cRio, roboRio, sensors, solenoid, pneumatic pistons to create a functional system on the robot

Education

Software Engineering, Bachelors in Engineers (BEng), Expected Graduation 2020

- University of Ontario Institute of Technology (UOIT), Oshawa, ON
 - GPA: 2.93/4.3

Relevant courses:

 Object Oriented Programming, Web Development, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Management Systems, Microprocessors and Computer Architecture, Software Design and Architecture, Systems Programming, Computer Networks, Intro. To Artificial Intelligence, Operating Systems, Software Project Management, Software Quality (647) 739-9188 | parth.suthar1@uoit.net 92 Hutcherson Sq., M1B 1C6, Toronto, ON github.com/suthar26 linkedin.com/in/parth-suthar

Projects

FRC Scouting app February 2017

Team 188 (https://tinyurl.com/Team188Scout) (github.com/frcteam188/frc-team188-website)

- Worked with another developer to create a web application to collect data on teams competing and provide real time information for the strategy team
- Designed the backend using express.js, PostgreSQL for data storage and pure HTML/CSS and JavaScript webpages

EZPay May 2016

FinHacks (Honourable mention) (github.com/VanshilShah/finhacks-2016-heroku)

- Collaborated with 5 individuals to develop a Web Application using **node.js** server to manage savings and pay bills through Text messages using Cisco **Tropo**
- Utilized **pug** file format and express.js framework

Checkpoint May 2016

CISCO DevNet Hackathon (Third Place) (github.com/VanshilShah/Checkpoint)

- Collaborated with 4 individuals to develop an Android application that rewards the runners every time they reach new checkpoints
- Maintained the application by using Cisco's Zeus to both provide runners and business owners the ability to oversee potential development
- Winner of the Zeus award for best utilization

Outpost Jan - April 2015

FRC Scouting (github.com/parth-r-patel/outpost-polymer)

- Worked in a group of 3 to create a web application using **Polymer 0.8** framework to collect data on the teams and view it real-time in order to enhance team's strategy process during competition
- Designed the backend using PHP/MySQL with our own REST API

Academic Projects

Galton board simulator and Convex hull finder

Data Structure, UOIT

- Programed a Galton board simulator using java to represent a normal distribution among randomly generated data and prove the Central Limit Theorem
- Developed a program using Java to find the convex hull for six different set of points in a CSV file and display on a graph

Automated Lighting system and garage door opener

Digital Systems, UOIT

 Programed and created smart automated lighting system prototype for a house using Arduino incorporated with a smart garage door opener as a set of smart home control unit

Comparative Study (DE vs PSO)

Design and Analysis of Algorithms, UOIT (github.com/suthar26/Comparative-Study-Project)

• Conduct a comparative study, DE vs PSO, over various benchmark functions, including High Conditional Elliptic, Bent Cigar, Discus, Rosenbrock's, Ackley's, Weierstrass, Grienwank's, Rastrigin's Katsura with different complexities.

Vanguard FRC

Data Management Systems, UOIT (github.com/suthar26/FRC-scouting-app)

 Built an Effective Database Management System to manage the data collection at FIRST Robotics Competition and analyze the data to provide usable statistics.